Guide to the Marjorie Perloff Papers M1504
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Marjorie Perloff papers
circa 1965-2005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Perloff, Marjorie
M1504
19 Linear Feet
Literary manuscripts, correspondence with writers, artists, fellow critics, and publishers, published essays and reviews, editorial and university administration files, and electronic discs.
no content
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marjorie Perloff, 2005. Accession 2005-097
Biography / Administrative History
Marjorie Perloff is one of the foremost American critics of contemporary poetry. Her work has been especially concerned with explicating the writing of experimental and avant-garde poets and relating it to the major currents of modernist and, especially, postmodernist activity in the arts, including the visual arts and cultural theory. She took her first degree at Barnard College, New York, followed by an M.A. and Ph.D. (in 1965) at CUA (Catholic University of America) in Washington DC. CUA also provided her first teaching post (as assistant and then associate professor) from 1966 to 1971. She moved to the University of Maryland as full professor in 1971, remaining there five years before moving to California in 1976. She has been a professor at Californian universities since 1976, with ten years at the University of Southern California, till 1986, and since then at Stanford University, becoming Sadie Dernham Patek Professor of Humanities in 1990. Her immense energies and enthusiasm as a writer and teacher have been devoted to creating a public for the work of writers whom many others have wanted to dismiss as too difficult, obscure, or marginal. Her own writing is always anything but that; as Frank Kermode has said, Marjorie Perloff is fun to read. She has never been a critic who wraps her insights in a daunting verbal carapace which only the truly intrepid can penetrate. She writes to explain, and always communicates her insights through vivid juxtapositions, formulations, and examples.
From The Encyclopedia of Literary Critics and Criticism, Edited by Chris Murray. (Fitzroy Dearborn, 1999)
Scope and Content of Collection
The Marjorie Perloff papers are divided into twelve series, respecting the original arrangement and box inventory provided by the donor. Series 1: Correspondence from Individuals, contains letter and notes from over seventy correspondees, including Robert Creeley, Barbara Guest, Ann Lauterbach, Robert Lowell, and Robert Pinsky. Nearly one third of the collection is held in Series Two: Article Files, primarily material relating to published articles, and to a lesser extent, papers delivered at conferences or lectures. Reviews and Offprints, Series 3, contains copies of articles where either Perloff's worked is reviewed, or Perloff is the reviewer. Several folders at the end of the series hold the contents of scrapbooks specific to some of Perloff's earlier works: "The Poetic Art of Robert Lowell"; "Frank O'Hara: Poet Among Painters"; and "The Poetics of Indeterminacy: Rimbaud to Cage." Invitations to Give Papers and Conference Materials are found in Series 4, and, in Series 5: Early Works, a ts of Perloff's Master's Thesis, and editorial, correspondence, and publicity files for her works on Yeats, Lowell, and O'Hara are housed here. Series 6 and 7 contain material from several of Perloff's more recent works, listed by title respectively: The Futurist Moment/21st Century Modernism; Radical Wittengenstein's Ladder/Radical Artifice; and Series 8: Poetry/Genre/Cage similarly holds material from her various editorial projects, collections of essays, and shorter works, including John Cage: Composed in America, Postmodern Genres, Poetry On and Off the Page, Dance of the Intellect, and Poetic License. Other Editorial Files not included in the previous series are found in Series 9, and Miscellaneous files regarding awards and honors, and a review of Erica Jong are located in Series 10. Series 11 contains material concerning Perloff's various university appointments and administrative matters. The final Series: Foundations/Centers/Fellowships Applications, Advising, and Consults, holds correspondence, applications, and other material regarding Perloff's involvement with various granting agencies and institutions as both a potential recipient and consultant.
Poetics; Modernism (Literature); Critics -- United States; Art and literature -- United States -- History -- 20th century; American poetry- -20th century- -History and criticism; Literature, Modern -- History and criticism; Arts, Modern- -20th century; Perloff, Marjorie
- Series 1: Correspondence from Individuals
  - Correspondence - to file (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fan Mail (not alphabetized) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, Donald (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Altieri, Charles (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Andrews, Bruce (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Antin, David (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ashbery, John (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bang, Mary Jo (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bedient, Calvin (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bergvall, Caroline (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bernstein, Charles (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bernstein, Charles (Continued) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bök, Christian (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boland, Eavan (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bromige, David (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - C Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cage, John (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Creeley, Robert (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - D Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Davenport, Doris (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Davenport, Guy (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Davie, Donald (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Davidson, Michael (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Davis, Lydia (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - de Campos, Augusto (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dembo, Larry (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - di Palma, Ray (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Djuric, Dubravka (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dorn, Ed (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dragomoschenko, Arkadii (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Drucker, Johanna (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - DuPlessis, Rachel Blau (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Duncan, Donald (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dydo, Ulla (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - E-F Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Eshleman, Clayton (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fraser, Kathleen (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - G Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Goldsmith, Kenneth (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Guest, Barbara (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - H Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hejinian, Lyn (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hoover, Paul (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Howe, Susan (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - I-K Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Kent (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Kenner, Hugh (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Kutnik, Jerzy (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - L Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Laughlin, James (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Lauterbach, Ann (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lazer, Hank (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Leibowitz, Herb (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lowell, Robert (includes 3 letters from Elizabeth Hardwick) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - M Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Martin, Stephen-Paul (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - McCaffery, Steve (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - McCormack, Karen (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Messerli, Douglas (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - N-Q Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Nicholls, Peter (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Owens, Rochelle (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Palmer, Michael (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Perelman, Bob (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pinsky, Robert (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Quartermain, Peter (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - R Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Rabaté, Jean-Michel (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rasula, Jed (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Raworth, Tom (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rawson, Claude (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Retallack, Joan (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - S Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - St. John, David (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Scalapino, Leslie (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Sieburth, Richard (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Silliman, Ron (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sommer, Pyotr (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Stimpson, Catharine (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - T-Z Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Tomlinson. Charles (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Tranter, John (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Treglown, Jeremy (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Von Hallberg, Robert (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Wakoski, Diane (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Waldrop, Rosmarie (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Watten, Barrett (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Weiss, Theodore (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Wellman, Mac (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wright, C.D. (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Series 2: Article Files
  - Stanford Humanities Conference April 22-25 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Eliot Response (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - After Language Poetry (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - After Language and Poetry: Revised paper and notes (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - James Tate Paper (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hejinian, Facture (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Teaching Experimental Poetries (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Letters and Commentary (9/11) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Akhmatova (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - MLA Paper (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Robert Lowell (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Yeats Paper - Davis (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Wittgenstein Provence (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Click and Drag (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pound Essay for Whide Box (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Oulipo Factor (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - UTQ - Nichol Review (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - UCLA Jan 24-25 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Beckett: Words and Music (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - John Kinsella - Intro (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Beckett for ACT (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Translating Brazilian Concrete (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - A New Ezra Pound (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lawrence Essay (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Revell / Apollinaire (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - By-Pass: A User's Manual (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Wittgenstein Paper for MSA (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Eliot Paper "Gerontion" (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Raworth Review (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Raworth Paper (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 40 Best - WLT (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Leigh Davis Review - Landfall (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Desert Island Genre (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Jasper Johns Essay (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Jasper Johns Xeroxes (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Homi Bhabha Paper (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Concrete Prose (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Ashbery for CP (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Ashbery Stand Review (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Rilke Essay and Notes (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Radio Forum - Notes and Everett Frost Materials (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rochelle Owens (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Emily Dickinson (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Stein - American Poet (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Roy Fisher Essay (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Blockbusters (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Von Hallberg (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mac Wellman - Preface (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Ashbery, Your Name Here (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Election Diary (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Foliadi Sao Paolo (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Pound/Duchamp -- Paris (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Symploke (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Jasper Johns for Computense University (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Serres Essay, Mailed July 20 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Logocinema of the Frontiersman, Yale Sept. 19 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Pound ITLS (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Outlaw Bible - APR, mailed Feb. 20, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - PMLA Yearbook (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Livre Noir du Comunisme (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Visible Language Essay Out in Fall due May, Give to Renee 6 July (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Celan Essay (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Preface - Susan Rankaitis Catalogue (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - De Campos Interview (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Salmagundi Essay, Response to Scholes - Mailed May 28 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Duchamp and Stein - Forum for Modern Language Studies (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cage Paper - Warsaw (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Mina Lay Paper for Maera and Keith Book: 1 copy and first draft (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hank Lazer (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Druckworks mailed Sept. 11 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - CL Review - Perelman (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Future of Literary Studies, Electronic Book Review, Phyllis Letter (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Gertrude Stein's Hemingway - 1st Version, Notes/Correspondence, mailed to Englad Feb. 13, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Smithson Essay (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Language Essay mailed to APR March 3 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cendrars / O'Hara Essay for YES: Anglo-Saxon Number, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Preface to Cendrars' Sky (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "Crisis in the Humanities" - mailed Oct. 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - MLA Poetry Talk - 2 copies and 1st Version (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - NRP Piece - Barbara Bush (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - California Criticism (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Cendrars / Pound (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - MLQ Position Paper (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Common Knowledge (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Ashbery / Flowchart / Notes (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Why Futurism Now? (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Wittgenstein: The Politics of War; 1st Version and Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Partisan Review, 1934-45, Notes for 1931 paper, both Pagany and Halpert Archive and Objectivists (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Common Knowledge Piece - "Little Review" (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Towards a Wittgenstein Poetics, 2 copies, Proof mailed Feb. 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Music Today - Cage piece due Jan. 31 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Berryman / Lowell Essay for APR: Original, 4 Copies, 1 copy w/ alternate notes, 2 copies - old (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Frye Review (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Carbon of Olson Review for MLR (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - New Republic Review: Hall, Remembering Poets (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Conrad, Imagining America and Stein Review for MLR, mailed Nov. 3, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Vendler Review 10 Copies (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Stevens / Pound Whose Era? Original + 3 Copies (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Elizabeth Bishop: The Course of a Particular (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Some Thoughts on Conferencing sent to Sulfur Oct. 19, 1983 - Original + 4 Copies (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Introduction to James Merrill (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Notes and Queries, Review of Michael Hamburger, mailed Sept. 16, 1983 to be published Summer/ Autumn 1984 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Preface - Contemporary Poets (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - British Poetry Since 1940 - 3 Copies (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - APR Column: German Lyric for Sept.-Oct. Issue mailed Monday, 27 June (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - The Avant-Garde Today for MLR - mailed 7 June '82, Proof mailed March 9, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Masterpiece Theater for ICLA - 2 copies collated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Letter to PNR Mailed 24 July (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - APR - Column for October, mailed on Oct. 28, Original and 2 copies (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Entries for Vinson, Contemporary Poets (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Seamus Heaney Review for Washington Post (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Davie Review (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Ellmann, Oxford Book review for MLR, 5 copies (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Creeley Essay for Boundary 2 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - The Two Poetries: An Introduction (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - John Yau Review for Meridian (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Review of Barnard, Sylvia Plath for WHR, mailed 25 July (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Bloom Review for American Literature (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Hall, Remembering Poets - Review (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - William Carlos Williams Newsletter Essay (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Transparent Selves: The Poetry of John Ashbery and Frank O'Hara, in press, Special American NO of YBES (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - APR Essay: Ammons / Ashbery and 1st v. of Post Review of JA, Houseboat Days (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Beckett Essay for Parnassus (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Olson Essay 6 Copies (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Poetry Nation Essay on Tomlinson (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Notes and Queries: Sagar, Ted Hughes Review copy 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - MLR Essay on Yeats, Uncollected Prose (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Charles Bernstein + Marjorie Perloff: A Conversation (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Beckett and Visual Text, Emory, Nov. 11-13 Old Versio, Vocovisual version, Lots of Figs (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Duchamp Paper - Pomona Mar. 23 revised version (and figures) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Duchamp Harvard Version of Paper Sept. 26 (inside previous folder) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Duchamp Notes (inside previous folder) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Figures Dada / Duchamp (inside Duchamp Paper - Pomona) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Differential Poetics Goldsmith / Kinsella, 1 original, 12 early drafts and 2 variants (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Caroline Bergvall (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Letters to the Editor Symploke (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - TLS Review 2 Copies, Creeley, mailed March 20 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Affiliations (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - TLS Review: Fisher, Crane (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Juliana Spahr (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Common Knowledge Essay 2 new + 2 old copies (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Poetry Flash Interview faxed 4 June 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Revell, Apollinaire, mailed 14 Dec. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Cunningham talk Oct. 12 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Beckett Review (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - John Cage - Mills College Thurs. Nov. 16 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Tolerance and Taboo - mailed to Elazar 10 June '92 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Rosmarie Waldrop Essay for HOW 2, mailed July 9 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Creeley Paper for Bridge (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Oppen Review for CL, sent April 25 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Tranter Review for Jacket (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Stein for British Academy (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Pound / Stevens - WSJ (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - London Review File Letters (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Cambridge Companion to WWI Avant-Garde Essay (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Ian Hamilton Finlay for TLS mailed 14 Jan. '05 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Goldsmiths - Beckett (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Beckett Paper Iowa, mailed Oct. 14 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Anthologies (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Beckett Essay July 1997 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Postmodernism / Fin de Siecle (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ammons Essay (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - John Cage's "What You Say" - mailed May 30, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Bruce Andrews for Aerial, mailed 19 Sept. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Gertrude Stein Grammarian mailed to Ravey for CHLC (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Stein - Cambridge (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Paper (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Language Poetry and Lyric Subject - Critical Inquiry mailed Sept. 14 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - TLS Essay - mailed on 28 Nov. '88 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Von Hallberg Dialogue (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - "After Free Verse" mailed to Charles Sept. 17 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Parshikov Preface and Book for Cydney Chadwick (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Scripsi Review - Bloodaxe Book mailed 15 July (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Language and the Lyric Subject, Paper and 1st draft, Sillman/Howe (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Clinton Piece (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Poems for Yang (INCLUDES DISK) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Peter Eisenman (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Viola Paper--MLA (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Theatre Symposium--Monday, March 11 ACT (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Textuality, for Renee (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Yasusada (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Bloom Article, Boston Review, 2,000 words (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Ron Silliman, Voice Paper for [Germ?] and Notes for Voice Problem (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Review of Delville (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Notes for Roy Fisher Paper (INCLUDES 8.5x14 paper) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Cutting-Edge Poetics-Aristotle/Howe (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Art Forum Review mailed 25 Aug. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Laurels from the Laureate--Plath/Hughes (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Peter Gizzi--Boston Book Review (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Wittgenstein's Aesthetic, Mailed to Parallax, May 6, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Treglown Piece 1st version and notes (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - 1956 (new) and early version with figures (but of computer version with changes) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - ALH 1956 A Step Away from Them (found inside previous folder, front) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Bill Viola (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Mark Jeffreys (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Interview with Akitoshi Nagahata (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Antin Interview and Introduction (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Rakosi mailed to JAS Dec 15 or so (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Pound-Fascism Materials (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Volume- Marshall Brown (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Russian Post-Modernism 2 copies and 1 original (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Making Room for the Avant-Garde" Harper Collins essay mailed 24 March (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Derrida Essay mailed Sat. 11 June 1988, 1 w/ footnotes, one corrected, 2 old, mailed revised version 16 Aug. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Harm's Other Way, Mac Wellman Essay (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - James Laughlin (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Witch of Truth--Laura Riding, Parnassus 1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Laurie Edson Paper (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Yeats's Sound Structures mailed for Yeats Annual (1995) May 21 correct copy in computer (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Jackson--Yale Symphosophia (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Duncan/ Levertov (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Russell Review--Washington Times (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Barthes Essay Photos and 8 negatives (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Barthes Essay--Figures (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Barthes Essay--1 original and 1 defective copy (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - 1931 Barbed Wire Entanglements (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Walder Benn Michaels Essay (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Normalizing John Ashbery Essay, for Jacket Magazine, John Tranter ed.[?] (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - New Literary History Paper (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Bridges Review (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Salfeur 37 - Visible Poetry (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Afterimages (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Mina Loy Papers (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - McCaffery, Howe, Raworth - Sulfur Piece (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - The Granite Butterfly - WCWR (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Nostromo for Wash Times (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Canon - Grolier (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Marinetti Marinetti MS (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Philip Larkin (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Sulfur 35 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Malina (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Bruce C: Conversation with MGP for Tom Beckett, The Difficulties (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - PoMo for Criticism (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Futurism Paper (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - MLQ Review of Boym (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Bachmann Review (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Niedecker Essay (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Larkin Paper for Parnassus (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Avant-Garde Lecture and Xeroxes PBK (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Malina - Sulfur #32 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Modern Epic: The World System from Goethe to Garcia Marquez, Franco Moretti: review by Perloff in EBR (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Series 3: Reviews and Offprints
  - Misc. reviews and mentions (1 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Misc. reviews and mentions (2 of 2) (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - reviews of Pound among poets (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - reviews of Stevens essay (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Misc. reviews / notices (1 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Misc. reviews / notices (2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - South Atlantic Bulletin - January 1979 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Charles Olson and "The Inferior Predecessors" (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Dada without Duchamp (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Cultural Liminality/Aesthetic Closure? (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Language Poetry and the Lyric Subject: Robert Silliman's Albany, Susan Howe's Buffalo (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Offprints (1-2 of 16) (Box 20, Folder 1011)
  - Offprints (3-8 of 16) (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Offprints (9-16 of 16) (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - The Poetic Art of Robert Lowell: Reviews (Othertype 23, Folder 1)
  - Frank O'Hara: Poet Among Painters: Reviews (Othertype 23, Folder 2)
  - The Poetics of Indeterminancy: Rimbaud to Cage: Reviews (Othertype 23, Folder 3)
- Series 4: Invitations to Give Papers/Conference Materials
  - The Centre for Modernist Studies, 2003-4 "Modernism, philosophy and psychoanalysis" (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Hendrix-Murphy Foundation Programs in Literature and Language (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - New York University (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Associates of the Stanford University Libraries 1997 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - 3rd Incontro Internacional de Poetas, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - University of London 1998 (Box 24, Folder 6)